# Yuri Adhikari

Active Public Trust

Security Clearance

Data enthusiast with 5+ years of experience, seeking a client-facing role to help decision makers measure performance, deal with uncertainty, and make data-driven decisions by applying best practices of data warehousing, data visualization, and business analytics.

s.yuri.adhikari@gmail.com 703-261-4131 0 Arlington, VA

> linkedin.com/in/yuriadhikari github.com/clementines

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Deloitte Consulting LLP - Arlington, VA

Consultant

Nov 2016 - Present

Provided client-facing development and analysis services on data warehousing projects for federal clients

- Developed an executive dashboard for the C-suite of a major federal research agency with 20K employees
- Supported legacy financial applications with 3K users, using best practices of ETL, data modeling, and design
- Utilized an agile development process to create weekly deliverables and pivot efforts based on client feedback

#### Vitality, Subs. of Discovery Holdings - Chicago, IL

Data Analyst

Sep 2014 - Nov 2016

Developed and analyzed processes to aid operations and strategy for a Software as a Service, health & wellness firm

- Evangelized the benefits of Business Intelligence, increasing adoption of the BI platform from 3% to 35%
- Identified risk factors and automated a quantitative basis to target retention efforts for at-risk clients
- Implemented basic data governance in several departments, enabling data-driven analysis of strategic initiatives
- Optimized and extended legacy production data models resulting in monthly cost savings of at least \$100k
- Defined and automated KPIs and SLAs for client-facing and support personnel to increase visibility and resolution
- Developed end-to-end processes of ETL, dimensional modeling, scripting, automation, and data visualization

#### Claraview, Div. of Teradata - Reston, VA

PS Consultant I / Associate Consultant

Jun 2012 - Jun 2014

Provided client-facing development and analysis services on business intelligence projects for Teradata clients

- Elicited requirements from a Fortune 100 client in telecommunications for a pro forma reporting application
- Developed an application and process that reduced 80 weekly labor-hours to 4 weekly labor-hours
- Delivered a prototype of novel executive views of RoIC for a Fortune 500 client in travel & hospitality
- Created a dimensional model utilizing an existing EDW and time-based calculations of asset-backed securities
- Generated ad hoc financial reports, helping the client increase cash flow and manage subleasing of assets
- Facilitated sessions with client's Business Intelligence team to improve data stewardship and reporting capability

# Configment LLC - Charlottesville, VA

**Summer 2011** 

Developed wireframes for servicing new entrepreneurs through the process of new venture creation

#### Booz Allen Hamilton - Arlington, VA

Intern

Summer/Winter 2010

Mapped a standardized process for the deployment and redeployment of the US Armed Forces

# **EDUCATION**

## University of Virginia - Charlottesville, VA

Sep 2007 - Jun 2012

B.S. in Systems and Information Engineering | B.A. in Cognitive Science | Minor in Mathematics

# **TECHNICAL**

Capabilities: Relational ETL, Big Data Integration, Dimensional Modeling, Process Automation, Ad Hoc Reporting, Data Visualization, Descriptive Analytics, Predictive Analytics, Data Stewardship

Frameworks: SQL Server (SSIS, SSRS), Teradata, Oracle, Qlik (QlikView, Qlik Sense), Cognos (Framework Manager), Python (NumPy, SciPy, Pandas, SciKit-Learn), HTML/CSS/JS (D3, MEVN), Hadoop (HDFS, Spark, Pig, Hive)

## TRAINING

Coursera Specialization: Executive Data Science from Johns Hopkins and Big Data from UC San Diego	2018
Deloitte DataViz Hackathon: Use Cases and Best Practices for Qlik, Tableau, and D3 (HTML/CSS/JS)	2017
Edward Tufte - Presenting Data and Information: Modern Theories on Data Visualization	2015
Teradata Factory & Claraview Bootcamp: Teradata SQL, Database Tuning, Cognos and BusinessObjects	2012